2023-07-22 03:27:32 INFO - Scenario 'Font settings: Check of text theme' start 2023-07-22 03:27:32 INFO - Setting application driver using the server on 'https://hub-cloud.browserstack.com/wd/hub' 2023-07-22 03:27:59 INFO - Application on platform 'ANDROID' is ready... 2023-07-22 03:27:59 INFO - Session id - e224048a5b61cabfc394954d328e8a8a59ce1ee0 2023-07-22 03:27:59 INFO - Step 0 - Close tutorial screen 2023-07-22 03:27:59 INFO - Button 'btnCloseTutorial' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:28:01 INFO - Step 1 - Welcome screen is opened 2023-07-22 03:28:02 INFO - Step 2 - Close welcome screen 2023-07-22 03:28:02 INFO - Button 'btnFindLibrary' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:28:02 INFO - Step 3 - Add library screen is opened 2023-07-22 03:28:04 INFO - Step 4 - Add library "LYRASIS Reads" on Add library screen 2023-07-22 03:28:04 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:28:06 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Clearing 2023-07-22 03:28:06 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Typing 'LYRASIS Reads' 2023-07-22 03:28:09 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:28:09 INFO - Step 5 - Account "LYRASIS Reads" is present on Accounts screen 2023-07-22 03:28:09 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:28:10 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:28:11 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:28:13 INFO - Step 6 - Enter credentials for 'LYRASIS Reads' account 2023-07-22 03:28:13 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:28:14 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:28:15 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:28:17 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:28:17 INFO - Locking credential with barcode 01230000000002 2023-07-22 03:28:17 INFO - There are books on the account: 2023-07-22 03:28:18 INFO - bookName: Apples Never Fall Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-07-22 03:28:18 INFO - Count of books on the account after opening account: 1 2023-07-22 03:28:18 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Clearing 2023-07-22 03:28:18 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Typing '01230000000002' 2023-07-22 03:28:20 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Clearing 2023-07-22 03:28:20 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Typing '********' 2023-07-22 03:28:22 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:28:27 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-07-22 03:28:28 INFO - Step 7 - Login is performed successfully 2023-07-22 03:28:49 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-07-22 03:28:49 INFO - Step 8 - Open Catalog 2023-07-22 03:28:49 INFO - Button 'tabCatalog' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:29:12 INFO - Step 9 - Open search modal 2023-07-22 03:29:33 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:29:34 INFO - Step 10 - Search 'available' book of distributor 'Bibliotheca' and bookType 'EBOOK' from "LYRASIS Reads" and save as 'bookNameInfo' 2023-07-22 03:29:34 INFO - Count of attempts to get random book name without bad symbols-2 2023-07-22 03:29:34 INFO - randomBookName: The Hidden 2023-07-22 03:29:34 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-07-22 03:29:35 INFO - Text Field 'Search value input' :: Sending keys 'The Hidden' 2023-07-22 03:29:38 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-07-22 03:29:41 INFO - Step 11 - Click GET action button on EBOOK book with 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-07-22 03:29:42 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-07-22 03:29:42 INFO - Button 'actionButton' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:29:49 INFO - Step 12 - Open EBOOK book with READ action button and 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-07-22 03:29:50 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-07-22 03:29:50 INFO - Label 'lblBookName' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:29:51 INFO - Step 13 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-07-22 03:29:51 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:29:52 INFO - Step 14 - Scroll page forward from 7 to 9 times 2023-07-22 03:29:53 INFO - Scrolling 7 times on reader epub screen 2023-07-22 03:30:11 INFO - Step 15 - Open font settings 2023-07-22 03:30:12 INFO - Button 'btnFontSettings' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:30:12 INFO - Step 16 - Change contrast to BLACK_TEXT_ON_WHITE 2023-07-22 03:30:12 INFO - Button 'setThemeLight' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:30:13 INFO - Step 17 - The BLACK_TEXT_ON_WHITE background is correct 2023-07-22 03:30:14 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-07-22 03:30:14 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-07-22 03:30:15 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-07-22 03:30:15 INFO -

CHAPTER

8

Beneath the depths of the ocean, according to these stories, an atmosphere exists adapted to the respiratory organs of certain beings, resembling in form the human race, possessed of surpassing beauty, of limited supernatural powers, and liable to the incident of death. They dwell in a wide territory of the globe, far below the region of fishes, over which the sea, like the cloudy canopy of our sky, loftily rolls.

—George Brisbane Scott Douglas,
“The Fisherman and the Merman,” 1901

THEN

Ruby

August

RUBY WAS WATCHING Yoga Man from the safety of the dark. She was sitting, wrapped in a duvet, on the draining board, her feet in the sink. The routine was familiar; she’d been watching him without fail every day, for so long that the sequences repeated in a pattern she could now predict. Today was headstand day.

Being awake at three thirty AM was standard for Ruby these days, now that a normal person’s regime, like having work hours and a social life, was no longer relevant. She dwelled in a permanent half-light; whenever an errant sunbeam edged around the closed curtains and sought her out, it felt as if it burned. The only time the curtains were open fully was at night, when she was watching Yoga Man. A guilty pleasure, perhaps even shameful, but in those silent hours, cocooned in the velvet dark and the warmth of the bedcover, she felt more alive than she had in a long time. His movements both soothed and ignited her. When he walked toward her at the end of the routine, to shut the blinds against the approaching dawn, she imagined he was looking at her, acknowledging her. He seemed to gaze straight into her eyes, though where she sat, behind glass, protected by the dark, he could never have seen her.

When it was over, Ruby would get down from her perch and go to bed, tying a scarf over her eyes to block out the light, sleeping until mid-afternoon. Just like Barbara, her boss, had said, after she’d driven Ruby home from work on the day she’d been signed off sick, yoga practice was meant to be good for your mental health. Barbara meant for her to take a class, but perhaps watching someone else do it was equally effective. It was certainly true that once she’d discovered Yoga Man, Ruby felt she was less depressed and more productive. He was inspirational: when she wasn’t watching him, or sleeping, she was working on her music.

Ruby had been spending more and more time playing, perfecting sections from Sibelius’s D Minor Concerto. The piece was fiendishly difficult, and while she played, she felt she had a sense of purpose, a hope that she might conquer it, do it justice, as only the best players could. Only when the callouses on the tips of her fingers started to bleed onto the ebony of the fingerboard and her shoulders screamed from the tension of the playing position would she wrap the instrument in its ancient duster and place it safely away. Only then would the bad thoughts seep in, along with the loneliness. She tried to keep playing until it was time to watch Yoga Man, but sometimes it wasn’t possible. Thank goodness, then, that in the past few weeks she’d felt a new awakening. She’d started to compose something herself; a piece that, when she was immersed in it, chased away the bad thoughts so completely that she was entirely made of music. It was as if when she played, she was losing herself in becoming a conduit for Sibelius or Mozart or Grieg. But when she sat down to compose, the conduit was something else, not a person. A spirit perhaps, but not a completely nice one. It had personality, this muse of hers.

The melody she was writing had appeared, fully formed, as she watched Yoga Man one night, and she’d scribbled it down, convinced it was something she’d heard before. She hummed it quietly, and its haunting beauty made her think of the ocean at night. The theme began with a tritone—the Devil’s interval—and in her head the first three notes were played slowly, almost tentatively, on a low flute echoed by a solo viola. Where had she heard it before? It turned out she hadn’t. The tune felt so complete, so filmic, and filled with a kind of foreboding. As she went deeper into the composition, it felt less as if someone else had written it, more that it was writing itself. And since then, every time she returned to the manuscript, it seemed like the notes were coming from another place, through her rather than from her. Her fingers held the pen that rested on the paper, and from it the music surged, unexpected, sometimes chilling, and utterly exquisite.

Because of the music, she’d never started the antidepressants that the doctor had given her. More than once she’d picked them up in the packet, taken out the leaflet and read the list of possible side effects, then put them back down again. The doctor had told her the pills would rebalance the chemicals in her brain, but the idea of that was more frightening than the bad thoughts. The pills might dull her creativity, which she already considered to be tenuous and fleeting. They might take away the desire to compose, and with it the first truly beautiful thing she’d created. It was too much to risk.

The tap dripped on her toe, bringing her back to the room. Across the way, Yoga Man was standing at the window, his hand on the pull for the blind. Ruby stared straight into his eyes, as she usually did. He appeared to be looking at her, and she enjoyed the sensation, the fantasy that he knew she was watching and was performing it all for her. Then, he cupped his hand over his eyes to shade them and pressed his face to the window. His body language transformed from relaxed to agitated. He could see her. He turned, dashed across to the wall where his light switches were. Suddenly the big window was plunged into darkness.

Ruby scrambled off the drainer, fell heavily on her side, and lay there on the tiles, breathing hard. After a minute she crawled toward the bed-sitting room, avoiding the windows in case the man was still standing there in his darkened room, peering out, wondering who it was that was spying on him.

It was impossible to sleep. Instead, as the sun rose, she worked on her composition, adding a movement that became chaotically discordant, spiky, and unpleasant. Reaching the final few bars, she decided that she hated every bit of it. She crumpled up the new section and tossed it into the bin.

The following day, Ruby practiced the Sibelius past the point at which her fingers hurt. She didn’t eat all day, so by the time night fell, she was beyond hunger, enjoying the light feeling of nothing in her stomach, her mind a flighty thing jumping between ideas without fulling exploring any single one, forgetting what she’d been thinking about, not really caring either. At the usual time, in the darkness, she parted the curtains and peeked toward Yoga Man’s window, hoping to see him there, in yoga pants and nothing else, just like normal. It was planks day today; she loved to see the straightness of his body, his taut backside the only interruption to the perfect line from head to shoulder, to heel. Disappointment stung: the blinds were drawn. Her private show was over, all of her fun spoiled. The yoga would go on, but she wasn’t privy to it, not anymore. Ruby felt nothing but shame and loss.

Back in the bed-sitting room, she opened the manuscript she’d been working on and stared at the hundreds of neatly drawn runs of notes. The work had grown, covering both sides of fifty or more pages, but she suddenly couldn’t remember why she’d even started it. The melody she’d been so entranced by, that she’d based the whole thing on, seemed trite, derivative. No one would want to hear this, let alone play it. Not even the Devil—especially not him. There was nothing mischievous or dark there, nothing clever or profound. It was all dull, repetitive, predictable. She got up, dropped the entire sheaf of papers into the recycling chute and climbed into bed. There, in a fit of recklessness, she shook four sleeping pills into her palm and crunched them between her teeth before lying down, closing her eyes, and letting the drugs drag her consciousness away.

Waking in the afternoon, Ruby realized she had only half an hour to make her appointment at the GP’s. She threw on some clothes and rushed out, hair and teeth unbrushed, bare feet shoved into old trainers. The doctor looked her up and down and briskly signed her off work for another six weeks. He peered at her over the top of his spectacles. “How are you finding taking the antidepressants?”

Ruby said, “Oh, fine. I feel much better, actually.”

“No side effects?”

“Nothing significant, no.”

She did not mention that she still had no plans to take even a single one.

The doctor gave her another prescription, which Ruby shoved in a pocket on her way out of the surgery. What would happen, she wondered, if she took all of the pills in one go? Would she die quickly, floating away in a blissful cloud of obliviousness? Or would her liver implode, causing untold pain and suffering? It would be interesting to find out, in a way. At least she would feel something other than shame, or loneliness.

On the tram, exhausted and listless, she stared out the window so that at first she didn’t notice him: Yoga Man was sitting two rows in front of her. She looked once, then away, wondering, Is that really him? She recognized the back of his head, the curve of his neck. Her heart began to pound. She pressed the button for the tram to stop, got up and went past him, holding on to the rail near the door as the vehicle slowed. Don’t make it too obvious, she told herself, and allowed herself only a short glance in his direction as she got off. He was staring right at her, a slight frown creasing his forehead. She panicked then, hurrying out the doors before they were fully opened, keeping her head down until the tram was out of sight.

Ruby trudged back to the flat in the rain. By the time she got there, she found that a plan had formed, seemingly of its own accord, a bit like the melody had done. There was a quiver of a thrill, that she was being guided by the muse again, but this time not just in music. She made no attempt to resist or to think it through: she walked in the door and got straight into the shower, turned it up as hot as she could bear it and began to scrub. Soon she’d washed away two weeks of grime, shampooed her hair three times. She shaved her armpits and legs, exfoliated her entire body the way she always used to do. She toweled herself dry, applied lotion, used tweezers to shape her eyebrows. She put makeup on and grabbed a dress out of her wardrobe that she hadn’t worn in months. There, she thought, admiring herself in the mirror. I’m unrecognizable.

You’re all dressed up with nowhere to go, said a mean voice inside her head.

I don’t have anywhere to go yet, she said to the voice. But maybe I will soon.

That night, she put on a pair of heels, stood in the dark, and watched the shadows play on the blinds of his living room, imagining the scene within. It was comforting to know that he was still doing the yoga, even if she couldn’t see it. That perfectly muscled body had to be maintained somehow.

Ruby went to bed and slept better than she had in weeks, without any sleeping pills, between clean sheets. The next day she dressed carefully, forced herself to eat a breakfast of scrambled eggs and set off to ride the tram.

There was no sign of him, so she rode all the way to the end of the line and back, getting off in the city center to sit and watch the crowds for a while. She was gratified to see that several young men noticed her, though she didn’t acknowledge their curious glances. Just yesterday she’d been invisible, a hunched and grubby thing, moving through the press of people without drawing a single eye. Apart from his. He’d looked at her. He’d seen her.

At the market, she bought an apple and ate it while she stood at the tram stop, waiting to get on, heading out of town again, only to come back in.

When he wasn’t on the next tram either, Ruby couldn’t hold back the disappointment. She stopped hoping but kept riding. There was no reason to go home, really. See? said the mean voice in her head. I told you.

The apple core was brown and spindly where she held it between thumb and forefinger, and she was about to admit defeat when suddenly, there he was, shuffling on board with his head down. After a moment his eyes swept the passengers with a kind of nervousness and paused, she thought, just for a second, on her. Ruby watched him from the side of her vision, her face turned away. Taller than she’d thought, with longish, wavy hair, dressed in a rather ill-fitting suit, Yoga Man had been waiting at the stop nearest the banks. He didn’t strike her as a banker, though: too alternative. A bead on a leather string peeped out from below his cuff, so that the impression was of a surfer who’d been to a job interview. As he passed her in the aisle, she looked straight at him, and their eyes met.

He paused. “Do I know you?”

“I don’t think so,” said Ruby, and smiled slightly, shrugging with her eyebrows before turning back to the window.

He didn’t move. “I’m so sure. You look really familiar. Do you ever go to the gym near the bypass?”

“No, not me.”

“Oh, okay.” He sounded disappointed in her answer.

“Wait,” she said, “are you saying I need to join a gym? That’s a bit rude.” Ruby straightened her dress and crossed her arms. She knew she wasn’t fat—she was far too thin, if anything, though it was true that she rarely exercised. Maybe he thought she needed to tone up.

“Of course not.” He started to stutter, and a blush rose in his cheeks. “I only meant that … I thought maybe I’d seen you around. My office is near the gym, that’s all. I didn’t mean …”

She watched him for a moment, astounded that anyone would be stumbling over their words because of something she’d said.

He went on, “I don’t even go there, myself. I hate gyms. It’s just, I just …” For an unsettling moment, she thought he was going to cry.

She placed a hand on his forearm. “It’s okay. I wasn’t offended. I was joking with you.”

The movement of the tram yanked his arm away, so that her hand hovered in the air for a beat, and they both stared at it before she took it back. He said, “I’m sorry, I don’t usually—I mean, I never … I’m just not good at talking to girls. I mean women.” He ran a hand through his hair, stared at his shoes, appeared to swallow. “I’m so sorry—I meant people.” Then he swung his bag onto his shoulder and pressed the bell for the tram to stop. Ruby wanted to grab hold of him, to make him stay exactly where he was.

“Honestly, it was nothing,” she said.

“No, it was a dumb thing to say. But you’re kind to say that. I’m really sorry.”

He was edging farther away from her.

“Wait,” she said. “I don’t know your name.”

Confusion crossed his face, as if he couldn’t work out why she would want to know his name. Then he met her gaze, and the blush rose to his cheeks once more. “It’s Gregor.” He raised his eyebrows in a question.

“Ruby.”

“Like the jewel,” he said, and then cringed as if he’d said something stupid.

The tram was slowing to a stop, and people were filling the gap between them as they prepared to get off. Although she wanted to say something clever to make him stay, to make him talk to her some more, to reassure him that he hadn’t offended her, all she could manage was, “See ya.”

The rest of the journey home passed in a blur. She wondered why he’d gotten off the tram early, whether he’d done it just to get away from her because he was embarrassed, or if he had somewhere else to be. He’d seemed to recognize her, which was both worrying and thrilling. It was possible he knew her from the estate or from seeing her around the city in the days before her world shrank to the size of her flat. Perhaps, when she’d still been at work, they’d shared a commute; perhaps she wasn’t as invisible as she thought she was.

At her apartment building she had so much nervous energy to burn that she ran up the stairs instead of taking the lift. She’d spoken to Yoga Man! He thought he knew her! He seemed nice! She checked her mailbox and found a letter from Sam, finally. Today was a good day indeed.

At three AM, Ruby was still awake but feeling almost ready to go to sleep. Her practice had gone really well: she’d mastered some of the more virtuosic sections of the concerto and remembered to stop before her arms started hurting. After that she’d written back to Sam, a slightly manic three-page ramble that began:

Sam! I think I’ve met someone. I mean, maybe not met someone, but then maybe that is what I’ve done. I’ve made a new friend anyway—probably? But I have a good feeling about him. You know how sometimes you just know? And I’m composing again, which is a big thing for me. You’ll have to hear it when it’s done. I think it might be good, and I’ve never thought that about anything I’ve written before …

She’d posted the letter, then spent two hours beginning to recreate her composition from the scraps of what she remembered. Despite the difficulty of the task, she eventually concluded that it had been a good thing to throw it out and start again. She had feared that her tricksy muse had gone, that the spirit of diabolus in musica had grown bored waiting and left her, but as soon as she started to hum the main theme, it returned, along with her passion. The piece crackled with an urgency that it had lacked in its previous incarnation. In her head she could hear an orchestra playing it; she could even picture herself performing the solo, an image so clear that she could see the exact blue of the dress she would wear, the curve of the stage and the lighting. She could envisage the rapt faces of the audience members, shivers traveling through them and right back to Ruby, on stage. And the applause, washing over her, endless waves of it.

Time was sucked away, and soon the night was almost over. It was just before dawn when she took her makeup off, and Ruby was fizzing with possibility, with positive thoughts of change. She made a pact with herself to start going to bed earlier, to train herself back into normality before she returned to teaching in a few weeks’ time. Perhaps she didn’t need to stay away so long; she felt so much better. She would ring Barbara and ask to return to work. And she would stop trying to spy on Gregor (she rolled the new name around in her head, relishing the roundness of the vowels, the soft consonants) because that was not normal behavior, was it? Even as she thought this, she went through to the kitchen and found herself looking over at Gregor’s apartment building, hoping to see him there, softly lit by a side lamp, tackling a tricky inversion.

The big window was dark, though this time the blinds were open. She turned the lights off and stood, imagining herself on the other side of the drop, standing in his living room, looking over here. The fantasy was so vivid that she could actually see the outline of herself in his window. She pressed a palm to her own window and gazed at the image of her future self, so content to be inside Gregor’s apartment, waiting perhaps to start the yoga routine that they would perform together now. He would teach her; she would be a good student, and the lessons would calm her anxious mind.

Then, she froze, fear chilling her, running up her spine. She rubbed her eyes and looked again. The outline she had just imagined had taken shape, become solid, a dark figure forming in front of her eyes as she stared: there really was someone there, standing in the shadowed room, looking out. Not Gregor; it was a woman.

Her panicked brain scrambled for an explanation. She kept darting her eyes away and looking back, hoping not to see it. Was it a hallucination? Just when she’d started to feel on top of things? Oh, she thought, perhaps it could be a reflection, somehow, of me, standing here. But when she took her own hand down from the glass, the figure’s hand remained, white against the surface of the window. And beyond the hand, looming from the darkness, a pale face like the moon, with dark eyes that stared into her own. The face came closer to the glass, almost pressing up against it, a ghostly vision. Ruby ducked down, trying to hide, even though it was too late: she’d been seen.

Whoever it was—whatever it was—turned and walked away, back into the room.

For a while Ruby stood gazing at the blank eye of the big window, heart pounding, wondering if she was dreaming. No, of course she wasn’t; she could feel the cold kitchen floor beneath her feet, the rim of the stainless-steel sink under her fingers. She blinked and the woman was back, standing in the same place, but this time there was a bundle in her arms. It looked like a baby. Holding the child with one arm, the woman placed the other hand on the window, palm out, fingers splayed. With the baby she seemed less like a ghost, more like a human, though Ruby was still afraid; the way she stared, as if in accusation. The way her hands clutched the child, and her eyes, unblinking. Who was this woman to Gregor? His wife? Girlfriend?

Oh, Gregor. Ruby felt the disappointment bodily, the sensation of falling from a height, and gripped the edge of the sink to stop herself stumbling. At the same time she chastised herself: Why was she so upset by this? She hadn’t lost anything, not really, because she hadn’t had anything to start with, only a glimmer of hope. In a sick kind of a way, she was glad to have seen the woman—wife, partner, whatever she was—because it meant that Ruby knew where she stood: back on firm ground, where good things only happened to other people, and all the best men were taken or not interested. Not that Gregor would have been interested in her. How would she have explained the spying, for a start?

The woman in Gregor’s darkened apartment continued to stare across the drop and into Ruby’s eyes. After what seemed like a very long time, the woman reached across for the blind cord and slowly rolled it down, keeping her eyes on Ruby until the very last second.

2023-07-22 03:30:15 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-07-22 03:30:15 INFO - Taking screenshot 2023-07-22 03:30:17 INFO - Test finished - logging out 2023-07-22 03:30:18 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:30:20 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:30:21 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:30:22 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:30:24 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Getting text from element 2023-07-22 03:30:25 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Getting text from element 2023-07-22 03:30:25 INFO - Button 'Log out' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:30:46 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Getting text from element 2023-07-22 03:30:47 INFO - isLoggerNullAfterAnnotation-framework.utilities.Logger@258fab80

2023-07-22 03:02:23 INFO - Scenario 'Font settings: Check of increasing and reducing the text size' start 2023-07-22 03:02:23 INFO - Setting application driver using the server on 'https://hub-cloud.browserstack.com/wd/hub' 2023-07-22 03:02:53 INFO - Application on platform 'ANDROID' is ready... 2023-07-22 03:02:53 INFO - Session id - 755a32c0ca5f562f550570bb880a76855cfba57f 2023-07-22 03:02:53 INFO - Step 0 - Close tutorial screen 2023-07-22 03:02:53 INFO - Button 'btnCloseTutorial' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:02:55 INFO - Step 1 - Welcome screen is opened 2023-07-22 03:02:56 INFO - Step 2 - Close welcome screen 2023-07-22 03:02:56 INFO - Button 'btnFindLibrary' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:02:56 INFO - Step 3 - Add library screen is opened 2023-07-22 03:02:57 INFO - Step 4 - Add library "LYRASIS Reads" on Add library screen 2023-07-22 03:02:57 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:03:00 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Clearing 2023-07-22 03:03:00 INFO - Text Field 'Search' :: Typing 'LYRASIS Reads' 2023-07-22 03:03:02 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:03:03 INFO - Step 5 - Account "LYRASIS Reads" is present on Accounts screen 2023-07-22 03:03:03 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:03:04 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:03:05 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:03:07 INFO - Step 6 - Enter credentials for 'LYRASIS Reads' account 2023-07-22 03:03:07 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:03:07 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:03:08 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:03:09 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:03:25 INFO - Locking credential with barcode 01230000000005 2023-07-22 03:03:25 INFO - There are books on the account: 2023-07-22 03:03:26 INFO - bookName: Animal Instinct Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-07-22 03:03:26 INFO - bookName: Fahrenheit 451 Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-07-22 03:03:26 INFO - bookName: Children of Virtue and Vengeance Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-07-22 03:03:26 INFO - bookName: Blessed Monsters Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-07-22 03:03:26 INFO - bookName: Alice's Adventures in Wonderland Distributor: Palace Marketplace 2023-07-22 03:03:26 INFO - Count of books on the account after opening account: 5 2023-07-22 03:03:26 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Clearing 2023-07-22 03:03:26 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Typing '01230000000005' 2023-07-22 03:03:28 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Clearing 2023-07-22 03:03:28 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Typing '********' 2023-07-22 03:03:30 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:03:36 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-07-22 03:03:36 INFO - Step 7 - Login is performed successfully 2023-07-22 03:03:57 INFO - Button 'Log ... action' :: Getting text from element 2023-07-22 03:03:58 INFO - Step 8 - Open Catalog 2023-07-22 03:03:58 INFO - Button 'tabCatalog' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:04:18 INFO - Step 9 - Open search modal 2023-07-22 03:04:39 INFO - Button 'Search' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:04:41 INFO - Step 10 - Search 'available' book of distributor 'Palace Marketplace' and bookType 'EBOOK' from "LYRASIS Reads" and save as 'bookNameInfo' 2023-07-22 03:04:41 INFO - Count of attempts to get random book name without bad symbols-3 2023-07-22 03:04:41 INFO - randomBookName: The Sickness of Lone Chief 2023-07-22 03:04:42 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-07-22 03:04:42 INFO - Text Field 'Search value input' :: Sending keys 'The Sickness of Lone Chief' 2023-07-22 03:04:45 INFO - Error details button is not present 2023-07-22 03:04:47 INFO - Step 11 - Click GET action button on EBOOK book with 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-07-22 03:04:49 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-07-22 03:04:50 INFO - Button 'actionButton' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:04:59 INFO - Step 12 - Open EBOOK book with READ action button and 'bookNameInfo' bookName on catalog books screen and save book as 'bookInfo' 2023-07-22 03:05:00 INFO - Label 'lblAuthor' :: Getting text from element 2023-07-22 03:05:01 INFO - Label 'lblBookName' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:05:01 INFO - Step 13 - Click READ action button on book details screen 2023-07-22 03:05:02 INFO - Button 'Read' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:05:02 INFO - Step 14 - Scroll page forward from 7 to 9 times 2023-07-22 03:05:02 INFO - Scrolling 7 times on reader epub screen 2023-07-22 03:05:17 INFO - Step 15 - Save font size as 'fontSize' 2023-07-22 03:05:17 INFO - context - NATIVE_APP 2023-07-22 03:05:17 INFO - context - WEBVIEW_org.thepalaceproject.palace 2023-07-22 03:05:19 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsStart+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-07-22 03:05:19 INFO -

This is a tale that was told to me by two old men. We sat in the smoke of a mosquito-smudge, in the cool of the day, which was midnight; and ever and anon, throughout the telling, we smote lustily and with purpose at such of the winged pests as braved the smoke for a snack at our hides. To the right, beneath us, twenty feet down the crumbling bank, the Yukon gurgled lazily. To the left, on the rose-leaf rim of the low-lying hills, smouldered the sleepy sun, which saw no sleep that night nor was destined to see sleep for many nights to come.

The old men who sat with me and valorously slew mosquitoes were Lone Chief and Mutsak, erstwhile comrades in arms, and now withered repositories of tradition and ancient happening. They were the last of their generation and without honor among the younger set which had grown up on the farthest fringe of a mining civilization. Who cared for tradition in these days, when spirits could be evoked from black bottles, and black bottles could be evoked from the complaisant white men for a few hours' sweat or a mangy fur? Of what potency the fearful rites and masked mysteries of shamanism, when daily that living wonder, the steamboat, coughed and spluttered up and down the Yukon in defiance of all law, a veritable fire-breathing monster? And of what value was hereditary prestige, when he who now chopped the most wood, or best conned a stern-wheeler through the island mazes, attained the chiefest consideration of his fellows?

Of a truth, having lived too long, they had fallen on evil days, these two old men, Lone Chief and Mutsak, and in the new order they were without honor or place. So they waited drearily for death, and the while their hearts warmed to the strange white man who shared with them the torments of the mosquito-smudge and lent ready ear to their tales of old time before the steamboat came.

"So a girl was chosen for me," Lone Chief was saying. His voice, shrill and piping, ever and again dropped plummet-like into a hoarse and rattling bass, and, just as one became accustomed to it, soaring upward into the thin treble —alternate cricket chirpings and bullfrog croakings, as it were.

"So a girl was chosen for me," he was saying. "For my father, who was Kask-ta-ka, the Otter, was angered because I looked not with a needful eye upon women. He was an old man, and chief of his tribe. I was the last of his sons to be alive, and through me, only, could he look to see his blood go down among those to come after and as yet unborn. But know, O White Man, that I was very sick; and when neither the hunting nor the fishing delighted me, and by meat my belly was not made warm, how should I look with favor upon women? or prepare for the feast of marriage? or look forward to the prattle and troubles of little children?"

"Ay," Mutsak interrupted. "For had not Lone Chief fought in the arms of a great bear till his head was cracked and blood ran from out his ears?"

Lone Chief nodded vigorously. "Mutsak speaks true. In the time that followed, my head was well, and it was not well. For though the flesh healed and the sore went away, yet was I sick inside. When I walked, my legs shook under me, and when I looked at the light, my eyes became filled with tears. And when I opened my eyes, the world outside went around and around, and when I closed my eyes, my head inside went around and around, and all the things I had ever seen went around and around inside my head. And above my eyes there was a great pain, as though something heavy rested always upon me, or like a band that is drawn tight and gives much hurt. And speech was slow to me, and I waited long for each right word to come to my tongue. And when I waited not long, all manner of words crowded in, and my tongue spoke foolishness. I was very sick, and when my father, the Otter, brought the girl Kasaan before me—"

"Who was a young girl, and strong, my sister's child," Mutsak broke in. "Strong-hipped for children was Kasaan, and straight-legged and quick of foot. She made better moccasins than any of all the young girls, and the bark-rope she braided was the stoutest. And she had a smile in her eyes, and a laugh on her lips; and her temper was not hasty, nor was she unmindful that men give the law and women ever obey."

"As I say, I was very sick," Lone Chief went on. "And when my father, the Otter, brought the girl Kasaan before me, I said rather should they make me ready for burial than for marriage. Whereat the face of my father went black with anger, and he said that I should be served according to my wish, and that I who was yet alive should be made ready for death as one already dead—"

"Which be not the way of our people, O White Man," spoke up Mutsak. "For know that these things that were done to Lone Chief it was our custom to do only to dead men. But the Otter was very angry."

"Ay," said Lone Chief. "My father, the Otter, was a man short of speech and swift of deed. And he commanded the people to gather before the lodge wherein I lay. And when they were gathered, he commanded them to mourn for his son who was dead—"

"And before the lodge they sang the death-song—O-o-o-o-o-o-a-haa-ha-a-ich-klu-kuk-ich-klu-kuk," wailed Mutsak, in so excellent an imitation that all the tendrils of my spine crawled and curved in sympathy.

"And inside the lodge," continued Lone Chief, "my mother blackened her face with soot, and flung ashes upon her head, and mourned for me as one already dead; for so had my father commanded. So Okiakuta, my mother, mourned with much noise, and beat her breasts and tore her hair; and likewise Hooniak, my sister, and Seenatah, my mother's sister; and the noise they made caused a great ache in my head, and I felt that I would surely and immediately die.

"And the elders of the tribe gathered about me where I lay and discussed the journey my soul must take. One spoke of the thick and endless forests where lost souls wandered crying, and where I, too, might chance to wander and never see the end. And another spoke of the big rivers, rapid with bad water, where evil spirits shrieked and lifted up their formless arms to drag one down by the hair. For these rivers, all said together, a canoe must be provided me. And yet another spoke of the storms, such as no live man ever saw, when the stars rained down out of the sky, and the earth gaped wide in many cracks, and all the rivers in the heart of the earth rushed out and in. Whereupon they that sat by me flung up their arms and wailed loudly; and those outside heard, and wailed more loudly. And as to them I was as dead, so was I to my own mind dead. I did not know when, or how, yet did I know that I had surely died.

"And Okiakuta, my mother, laid beside me my squirrel-skin parka. Also she laid beside me my parka of caribou hide, and my rain coat of seal gut, and my wet-weather muclucs, that my soul should be warm and dry on its long journey. Further, there was mention made of a steep hill, thick with briers and devil's-club, and she fetched heavy moccasins to make the way easy for my feet.

"And when the elders spoke of the great beasts I should have to slay, the young men laid beside me my strongest bow and straightest arrows, my throwing-stick, my spear and knife. And when the elders spoke of the darkness and silence of the great spaces my soul must wander through, my mother wailed yet more loudly and flung yet more ashes upon her head.

"And the girl, Kasaan, crept in, very timid and quiet, and dropped a little bag upon the things for my journey. And in the little bag, I knew, were the flint and steel and the well-dried tinder for the fires my soul must build. And the blankets were chosen which were to be wrapped around me. Also were the slaves selected that were to be killed that my soul might have company. There were seven of these slaves, for my father was rich and powerful, and it was fit that I, his son, should have proper burial. These slaves we had got in war from the Mukumuks, who live down the Yukon. On the morrow, Skolka, the shaman, would kill them, one by one, so that their souls should go questing with mine through the Unknown. Among other things, they would carry my canoe till we came to the big river, rapid with bad water. And there being no room, and their work being done, they would come no farther, but remain and howl forever in the dark and endless forest.

"And as I looked on my fine warm clothes, and my blankets and weapons of war, and as I thought of the seven slaves to be slain, I felt proud of my burial and knew that I must be the envy of many men. And all the while my father, the Otter, sat silent and black. And all that day and night the people sang my death-song and beat the drums, till it seemed that I had surely died a thousand times.

"But in the morning my father arose and made talk. He had been a fighting man all his days, he said, as the people knew. Also the people knew that it were a greater honor to die fighting in battle than on the soft skins by the fire. And since I was to die anyway, it were well that I should go against the Mukumuks and be slain. Thus would I attain honor and chieftainship in the final abode of the dead, and thus would honor remain to my father, who was the Otter. Wherefore he gave command that a war party be made ready to go down the river. And that when we came upon the Mukumuks I was to go forth alone from my party, giving semblance of battle, and so be slain."

"Nay, but hear, O White Man!" cried Mutsak, unable longer to contain himself. "Skolka, the shaman, whispered long that night in the ear of the Otter, and it was his doing that Lone Chief should be sent forth to die. For the Otter being old, and Lone Chief the last of his sons, Skolka had it in mind to become chief himself over the people. And when the people had made great noise for a day and a night and Lone Chief was yet alive, Skolka was become afraid that he would not die. So it was the counsel of Skolka, with fine words of honor and deeds, that spoke through the mouth of the Otter.

"Ay," replied Lone Chief. "Well did I know it was the doing of Skolka, but I was unmindful, being very sick. I had no heart for anger, nor belly for stout words, and I cared little, one way or the other, only I cared to die and have done with it all. So, O White Man, the war party was made ready. No tried fighters were there, nor elders, crafty and wise—naught but five score of young men who had seen little fighting. And all the village gathered together above the bank of the river to see us depart. And we departed amid great rejoicing and the singing of my praises. Even thou, O White Man, wouldst rejoice at sight of a young man going forth to battle, even though doomed to die.

"So we went forth, the five score young men, and Mutsak came also, for he was likewise young and untried. And by command of my father, the Otter, my canoe was lashed on either side to the canoe of Mutsak and the canoe of Kannakut. Thus was my strength saved me from the work of the paddles, so that, for all of my sickness, I might make a brave show at the end. And thus we went down the river.

"Nor will I weary thee with the tale of the journey, which was not long. And not far above the village of the Mukumuks we came upon two of their fighting men in canoes, that fled at the sight of us. And then, according to the command of my father, my canoe was cast loose and I was left to drift down all alone. Also, according to his command, were the young men to see me die, so that they might return and tell the manner of my death. Upon this, my father, the Otter, and Skolka, the shaman, had been very clear, with stern promises of punishment in case they were not obeyed.

"I dipped my paddle and shouted words of scorn after the fleeing warriors. And the vile things I shouted made them turn their heads in anger, when they beheld that the young men held back, and that I came on alone. Whereupon, when they had made a safe distance, the two warriors drew their canoes somewhat apart and waited side by side for me to come between. And I came between, spear in hand, and singing the war-song of my people. Each flung a spear, but I bent my body, and the spears whistled over me, and I was unhurt. Then, and we were all together, we three, I cast my spear at the one to the right, and it drove into his throat and he pitched backward into the water.

"Great was my surprise thereat, for I had killed a man. I turned to the one on the left and drove strong with my paddle, to meet Death face to face; but the man's second spear, which was his last, but bit into the flesh of my shoulder. Then was I upon him, making no cast, but pressing the point into his breast and working it through him with both my hands. And while I worked, pressing with all my strength, he smote me upon my head, once and twice, with the broad of his paddle.

"Even as the point of the spear sprang out beyond his back, he smote me upon the head. There was a flash, as of bright light, and inside my head I felt something give, with a snap—just like that, with a snap. And the weight that pressed above my eyes so long was lifted, and the band that bound my brows so tight was broken. And a great gladness came upon me, and my heart sang with joy.

"This be death, I thought; wherefore I thought that death was very good. And then I saw the two empty canoes, and I knew that I was not dead, but well again. The blows of the man upon my head had made me well. I knew that I had killed, and the taste of the blood made me fierce, and I drove my paddle into the breast of the Yukon and urged my canoe toward the village of the Mukumuks. The young men behind me gave a great cry. I looked over my shoulder and saw the water foaming white from their paddles—"

"Ay, it foamed white from our paddles," said Mutsak. "For we remembered the command of the Otter, and of Skolka, that we behold with our own eyes the manner of Lone Chief's death. A young man of the Mukumuks, on his way to a salmon trap, beheld the coming of Lone Chief, and of the five score men behind him. And the young man fled in his canoe, straight for the village, that alarm might be given and preparation made. But Lone Chief hurried after him, and we hurried after Lone Chief to behold the manner of his death. Only, in the face of the village, as the young man leaped to the shore, Lone Chief rose up in his canoe and made a mighty cast. And the spear entered the body of the young man above the hips, and the young man fell upon his face.

"Whereupon Lone Chief leaped up the bank war-club in hand and a great war-cry on his lips, and dashed into the village. The first man he met was Itwilie, chief over the Mukumuks, and him Lone Chief smote upon the head with his war-club, so that he fell dead upon the ground. And for fear we might not behold the manner of his death, we too, the five score young men, leaped to the shore and followed Lone Chief into the village. Only the Mukumuks did not understand, and thought we had come to fight; so their bow-thongs sang and their arrows whistled among us. Whereat we forgot our errand, and fell upon them with our spears and clubs; and they being unprepared, there was great slaughter—"

"With my own hands I slew their shaman," proclaimed Lone Chief, his withered face a-work with memory of that old-time day. "With my own hands I slew him, who was a greater shaman than Skolka, our own shaman. And each time I faced a man, I thought, 'Now cometh Death; and each time I slew the man, and Death came not. It seemed the breath of life was strong in my nostrils and I could not die—"

"And we followed Lone Chief the length of the village and back again," continued Mutsak. "Like a pack of wolves we followed him, back and forth, and here and there, till there were no more Mukumuks left to fight. Then we gathered together five score men-slaves, and double as many women, and countless children, and we set fire and burned all the houses and lodges, and departed. And that was the last of the Mukumuks."

"And that was the last of the Mukumuks," Lone Chief repeated exultantly. "And when we came to our own village, the people were amazed at our burden of wealth and slaves, and in that I was still alive they were more amazed. And my father, the Otter, came trembling with gladness at the things I had done. For he was an old man, and I the last of his sons. And all the tried fighting men came, and the crafty and wise, till all the people were gathered together. And then I arose, and with a voice like thunder, commanded Skolka, the shaman, to stand forth—"

"Ay, O White Man," exclaimed Mutsak. "With a voice like thunder, that made the people shake at the knees and become afraid."

"And when Skolka had stood forth," Lone Chief went on, "I said that I was not minded to die. Also, I said it were not well that disappointment come to the evil spirits that wait beyond the grave. Wherefore I deemed it fit that the soul of Skolka fare forth into the Unknown, where doubtless it would howl forever in the dark and endless forest. And then I slew him, as he stood there, in the face of all the people. Even I, Lone Chief, with my own hands, slew Skolka, the shaman, in the face of all the people. And when a murmuring arose, I cried aloud—"

"With a voice like thunder," prompted Mutsak.

"Ay, with a voice like thunder I cried aloud: 'Behold, O ye people! I am Lone Chief, slayer of Skolka, the false shaman! Alone among men, have I passed down through the gateway of Death and returned again. Mine eyes have looked upon the unseen things. Mine ears have heard the unspoken words. Greater am I than Skolka, the shaman. Greater than all shamans am I. Likewise am I a greater chief than my father, the Otter. All his days did he fight with the Mukumuks, and lo, in one day have I destroyed them all. As with the breathing of a breath have I destroyed them. Wherefore, my father, the Otter, being old, and Skolka, the shaman, being dead, I shall be both chief and shaman. Henceforth shall I be both chief and shaman to you, O my people. And if any man dispute my word, let that man stand forth!'

"I waited, but no man stood forth. Then I cried: 'Hoh! I have tasted blood! Now bring meat, for I am hungry. Break open the caches, tear down the fish-racks, and let the feast be big. Let there be merriment, and songs, not of burial, but marriage. And last of all, let the girl Kasaan be brought. The girl Kasaan, who is to be the mother of the children of Lone Chief!'

"And at my words, and because that he was very old, my father, the Otter, wept like a woman, and put his arms about my knees. And from that day I was both chief and shaman. And great honor was mine, and all men yielded me obedience."

"Until the steamboat came," Mutsak prompted.

"Ay," said Lone Chief. "Until the steamboat came."

2023-07-22 03:05:19 INFO - pageSourceWithSettingsEnd+++++++++++++++++++++++++ 2023-07-22 03:05:19 INFO - Taking screenshot 2023-07-22 03:05:21 INFO - Test finished - logging out 2023-07-22 03:05:22 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:05:24 INFO - Button 'tabSettings' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:05:25 INFO - Button 'Accounts' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:05:26 INFO - Button 'LYRASIS Reads' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:05:28 INFO - Text Field 'Card' :: Getting text from element 2023-07-22 03:05:28 INFO - Text Field 'Pin' :: Getting text from element 2023-07-22 03:05:29 INFO - Button 'Log out' :: Clicking 2023-07-22 03:05:50 INFO - Button 'Log in' :: Getting text from element 2023-07-22 03:05:50 INFO - isLoggerNullAfterAnnotation-framework.utilities.Logger@258fab80